At some point in our lives, most of us have attended a school or university lecture.
在我们生命中的某个时刻，我们大多数人都参加过学校或大学的讲座。
These learning sessions give us some insightful nugget of knowledge or can be something we yawn through, trying to keep awake.
这些学习课程教授我们一些有深刻见解的宝贵知识，或者也可能是我们打着哈欠、努力保持清醒熬过的东西。
Whatever our experience, lectures have been and still are the most common teaching method in education.
无论我们的经历如何，讲座一直以来都是，并且仍然是教育中最常见的教学方法。
But will they exist in the future?
但它们在未来还会存在吗？
With the growth of the internet and so much information at our fingertips, you may think there is no need to gather together at a fixed location clutching a handful of textbooks.
随着互联网的发展，大量信息触手可及，你可能会认为没有必要在一个固定的地点聚在一起，手里还抓着几本教科书。
BBC journalist Matt Pickles, says "research has shown that students remember as little as 10 per cent of their lectures just days afterwards."
BBC记者马特·皮克尔斯说：“研究表明，学生们在听完讲座几天后，仅仅只能记住其中的10%。”
Professor Carl Wieman, who campaigns against the traditional lecture, felt talking at students and expecting them to absorb knowledge was not that effective so he introduced 'active learning' that encourages problem solving in small groups.
卡尔·维曼教授反对传统的授课方式，他认为对着学生讲话并期望他们吸收知识并不是那么有效，所以他引入了“主动学习”方法，鼓励学生以小组形式解决问题。
He listens to them and guides their discussions.
他倾听并指导他们的讨论。
The result has been improved exam results.
结果是学生的考试成绩提高了。
Other new alternatives to the lecture have included peer-to-peer learning and project-based learning that enable students to link up and work collaboratively on projects such as building a computer game.
其他替代传统讲座的新方法包括同伴学习和基于项目的学习，这些方法使学生能够沟通联系，在诸如制作电脑游戏等项目上合作开展工作。
Sometimes the lecture room is not conducive to learning; a boring, colourless room is not necessarily an inspiring place for stretching the mind.
有时，教室并不有利于学习；一个枯燥、毫无色彩的房间不一定是扩展思维的好地方。
At the Massachusetts Institute of Technology two lecture rooms have been refitted to allow students to sit around small tables with screens showing animated simulations to help them visualise concepts.
在麻省理工学院，有两个教室经过了改装，让学生们可以围坐在小桌子旁，屏幕上展示着动画模拟，以帮助他们形象化理解概念。
But new learning methods can come at a high financial cost compared to the relatively cheap way of being taught face-to-face by an academic.
但是，与教师面对面教学这种相对便宜的方式相比，新的学习方法可能会带来高昂的经济成本。
The real issue according to Professor Dan Butin, founding dean of the school of education and social policy at Merrimack College in Massachusetts, is that "Academics put thousands of hours of work into their books and much less time into thinking about the effectiveness of their teaching style."
马萨诸塞州梅里马克学院教育与社会政策学院的创始院长丹·布廷教授认为，真正的问题是“学者们投入数千个小时在他们的著作上，而花在思考自己教学方式有效性上的时间却少得多。”
But he says "the lecture has survived because research, not teaching, determines the success of a university and its academics."
但他也说：“课程之所以能延续下来，是因为决定一所大学及其学者成功的是研究，而不是教学。”
So if research quality is a measure of a university's success and money is tight, then the lecture could be here for a little longer.
所以，如果学术研究质量是衡量一所大学成功的标准，而且资金紧张，那么课程可能还会存在一段时间。
How does that make you feel?
这让你有什么感受呢？
How would you improve your lectures?
你会如何改进讲座呢？